Thomas Henry Seymour Papers
Connecticut Historical Society
Thomas Henry Seymour papers
1781 - 1880
Connecticut Historical Society
Seymour, Thomas Henry
Collection consists of letters, financial, legal, and military papers, printed matter, speeches and essays, diaries, jottings, ephemera, scrapbooks, and personal effects. Also included are some papers of Thomas H. Seymour's grandfather and father, Thomas Seymour and Henry Seymour.
5.8 linear feet (14 boxes)
Related Material
An index of catalog cards is available to assist item level access to related material in other collections. Access is through writer, recipient and date. The card catalog is located in the Research Center reading room. A listing of the Mexican War material in the Thomas H. Seymour papers is available.
Biographical Sketch
Thomas Henry Seymour was born in Hartford, Connecticut on September 29, 1807. He was the son of Henry Seymour (1764-1846) and Jane Ellery (1766-1851) and grandson of Colonel Thomas Seymour(1735-1829), the first Mayor of Hartford.
Seymour was educated in the public schools of Hartford and graduated in 1829 from Captain Alden Partridge's Military Institute in Middletown, Connecticut. He became editor of a Democratic paper, The Jeffersonian, as early as 1832. He studied law and was admitted to the bar on May 19, 1838. Active in military affairs, Seymour was chosen captain of the Hartford Light Guard(1837-1841). He was also a Mason and member of the Knights Templar.
Seymour served as a probate judge of the Hartford District (1836-1838) and as a Quartermaster General (1837-1838). He was elected as a Democrat to the Twenty-eighth Congress (1843-1845) but declined renomination. In 1847 he was commissioned Major of the Connecticut Infantry and the 9th U. S. Infantry, the New England regiment of volunteers raised for service in the Mexican War. He led the successful assault on the fortress of Chapultepec (1847) and was promoted to Colonel. He took part in the capture of Mexico and was honorably mustered out of the army July 25, 1848.
Unsuccessful in his first campaign (1849), Seymour was elected Governor of Connecticut in 1850. He resigned in 1853 when he was appointed by President Franklin Pierce as Minister to Russia, a position he held for four years. After traveling abroad, Seymour returned to the United States in 1858. When the Civil War began he opposed military measures against the Confederacy, and throughout the war he was the leader of the Connecticut Peace Democrats. After an unsuccessful run for Governor in 1863, Seymour retired from political life. A lifelong bachelor, Seymour lived in Hartford with his sister, Mary Ellery Seymour. He died in Hartford on September 3, 1868.
Note: Thomas H. Seymour has been cited in some secondary sources as Thomas "Hart" Seymour. There is no evidence in the Seymour papers that his middle name was Hart, however, there are several references to the middle name Henry. These include letters to his parents signed "Thomas Henry," family letters addressed to him as "Henry," "Harry," or "H," and his admittance to the bar as "Thomas Henry Seymour." In the Connecticut Historical Society's accession book and in CHS correspondence with him he is addressed as "Thomas Henry." His tombstone inscription at Cedar Hill Cemetery in Hartford also lists him as Thomas Henry Seymour. As the Historical Society has no record of the middle name "Hart," it has followed the available documentation and listed his middle name as Henry.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of letters to and from Thomas H. Seymour (a number written in French, Spanish, Russian, and Italian) and related material, financial papers (personal and professional), legal papers (personal and professional), military papers, printed material, speeches and essays written by Thomas H. Seymour, diaries, jottings, ephemera, scrapbooks, and personal items. The collection also contains two folders of papers belonging to Seymour's grandfather, Thomas Seymour (1735-1829), and father, Major Henry Seymour (1764-1846).
Arrangement
Materials are organized into twelve series, and two sub-series based on form and creator.
Series I: Correspondence consists primarily of letters and related material to Thomas H. Seymour. The letters cover his entire professional career, including his legal work, his participation in the Mexican War, his years in the House of Representatives, as Governor of Connecticut, and as Ambassador to Russia. The series contains a number of letters from family members including his brother William Seymour and his sister Mary Seymour. Other correspondents include John Danforth, Colin McCrae Ingersoll, Franklin Pierce, and Josiah Pierce, Jr.
Series II: Financial papers consists of bills, receipts, lists of expenses, and promissory notes for the Thomas H. Seymour household. Some items are written in French or Russian.
Series III: Legal papers consists of summons, depositions, writs, letters of administration, fee schedules, naturalization papers, inventories, testimonials, related newspaper clippings. The series also includes insurance claims for Mary E. Seymour and Samuel Seymour, and Thomas H. Seymour's admittance as an Attorney and Counsellor at Law, May 19, 1838. Inventory of the estate of Captain Thomas Seymour. Papers relating to the estate of Harrison Otis, 1873-1874.
Series IV: Military papers consists of inventories, contracts, bills, receipts, post returns, commissions, enlistment lists, reports, orders, and supporting correspondence related to Thomas H. Seymour's tenure as Quartermaster General, commanding officer of the Hartford Light Guard, and his service in the Mexican War.
Sub-series A: Quartermaster General Papers consists of inventories, contracts, bills and receipts with related correspondence, covering the period Thomas H. Seymour and some of his predecessors served as Quartermaster General.
Sub-series B: Military service papers consists of post returns, commissions, enlistment lists, reports, orders, court martial reports, receipts, and related correspondence. Material is primarily from Thomas H. Seymour's military service in the Mexican War.
Series V: Printed material consists of copies of newspaper clippings, ceremonials, advertisements, and circulars. Some items are in French and Russian.
Series VI: Speeches and essays consists of manuscripts, drafts of, and notes for speeches and essays written and delivered by Thomas H. Seymour throughout his career. Topics include Russia, the Bill of Rights, impeachment, history, the election, and the Mexican War.
Series VII: Diaries consists of Thomas H. Seymour's diaries, commonplace books, notes, jottings, and related material. Notes and jottings are on slips of paper of various sizes, some written by Seymour and many by other people. Some notes are in French and Russian. Jottings include brief notes and memoranda, some made rapidly, often on chance bits of paper, notes on French vocabulary, poetry, lists of souvenirs, guest lists, newspaper clippings, and notes on political, military and social issues. Most items are undated.
Series VIII: Ephemera consists of invitations, business cards, calling cards, lock of hair, hymns, poetry, botanical specimens, newspaper clippings, dance cards, at home cards, tickets, and theater and concert programs. Most are undated. Items are filed in random order.
Series IX: Scrapbooks consists of Thomas H. Seymour's scrapbook of newspaper clippings and copy of the scrapbook.
Series X: Personal items consists of wallet and notebooks belonging to Thomas H. Seymour.
Series XI: Henry Seymour papers consists of letters and receipts belonging to Thomas H. Seymour's father, Major Henry Seymour (1764-1846).
Series XII: Thomas Seymour papers consists of correspondence, receipts, and promissory notes belonging to Thomas H. Seymour's grandfather, Thomas Seymour (1735-1807).
Materials in this collection are arranged chronologically in each series to compliment access points from the card catalog.
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the collection. Some items in fragile condition. Preservation copy available for fragile items.
Accruals
The collection is open, additional material is not expected.
Subject Headings
Personal Names
Ingersoll, Colin McCrae.; Sigourney, Lydia Howard Huntley, 1791-1865.
Subjects
Slavery United States Anti-slavery movements.
Geographic Names
United States History War with Mexico, 1845-1848.; Russian Soviet Federated Socialist Republic Description and travel.
Genre Forms
Holographs; holographs, signed; printed forms completed in manuscript.
Contents:
- I. Correspondence
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour; copies of letters to and concerning the Secretary of War., 1830-1840; (12 items) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., 1841-1842; (4 items) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour; petitions and letters to theSenate and House of Representatives; manuscript copy of letter from John Quincy Adams., 1843; (22 items) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour; drafts of letters from Thomas H. Seymour; resolutions of the Anti-Slavery Society in New York., January - May, 1844; (18 items) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour; letter fragment., 1844; (15 items) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., July - December, 1844; (15 items) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letters primarily to Thomas H. Seymour; letters between Thomas H. Seymour and his parents; copy of House of Representatives Bill 501., January - May, 1845; (21 item) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour; Seymour's copies of his letters; newspaper clippings of poems., June - December, 1845; (9 items) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour; letters from William Seymour to his parents., 1846; (15 items) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour; War Department General Orders., January - June, 1847; (9 items) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour; two letters to Josiah Chadbourn from Joseph Chadbourn; drafts of letters and typed copy of letter by Thomas H. Seymour; newspaper clippings., July - December, 1847; (22 items) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letters to and from Thomas H. Seymour; newspaper clipping enclosures., 1848; (13 items) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour; copies of letters of reference for Major Thompson Brown; one letter in Russian., 1849; (22 items) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour, including three anonymous valentine letters., January - June, 1850; (17 items) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour; copy of Mexican newspaper clipping., July - December, 1850; (8 items) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., 1851; (17 items) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letters primarily to Thomas H. Seymour., January - June, 1852; (15 items) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., July - December, 1852; (12 items) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., January, 1853; (25 items) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., February, 1853; (24 items) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., March, 1853; (30 items) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., April, 1853; (15 items) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and concerning Thomas H. Seymour., May 1853; (27 items) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Letters primarily to Thomas H. Seymour., June 1853; (24 items) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., July - August, 1853; (14 items) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., September - October, 1853; (12 items) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour; telegram to Mary Seymour., November - December, 1853; (25 items) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Letters primarily to Thomas H. Seymour; manuscript copy of article from the Journal de St. Petersburg., January - April, 1854; (19 items) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour and supporting documents (nine in French)., May - August, 1854; (20 items) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour and supporting documents (one in French and one in Russian)., September - December, 1854; (16 items) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Letters primarily to Thomas H. Seymour and supporting documents., January - February, 1855; (13 items) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour and supporting documents (three in French and two in Russian)., March - April, 1855; (15 items) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., May - June, 1855; (7 items) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Letters primarily to Thomas H. Seymour (two in Russian)., July -August, 1855; (20 items) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour (two in French, two in Russian)., September - October, 1855; (20 items) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour (two in French)., November, 1855; (13 items) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour (one in Russian)., December, 1855; (24 items) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour (three in French)., January, 1856; (19 items) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour (one in French)., February, 1856; (20 items) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour; newspaper clipping (poem)., March, 1856; (7 items) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., April, 1856; (15 items) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour (three in French) with related material., May, 1856; (17 items) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Letters primarily to Thomas H. Seymour (one in French)., June, 1856; (12 items) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour (one in French)., July, 1856; (10 items) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour (six in French)., August, 1856; (12 items) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour (two in French)., September, 1856; (5 items) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour (one in French); newspaper clipping (poem by Lydia H. Sigourney)., October, 1856; (14 items) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., November, 1856; (5 items) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour (one in French, two in Russian)., December, 1856; (13 items) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour (one in Russian)., January - February, 1857; (11 item) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour with related material (one in French)., March - April, 1857; (10 items) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour (two in French)., May - June 1857; (21 item) (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., July - August, 1857; (11 item) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour with related material (one in French)., September - October, 1857; (16 items) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour with related material (one in French)., November - December, 1857; (19 items) (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Letters to and from Thomas H. Seymour (two in French)., January - February, 1858; (9 items) (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour with supporting material (three in French, three in Russian)., March - April, 1858; (21 items) (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour (one in French)., May - June, 1858; (9 items) (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., May - June, 1858; (9 items) (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour with related material., September - October, 1858; (9 items) (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., November - December, 1858; (4 items) (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour with related material; draft of letter from Thomas H. Seymour., January - February, 1859; (5 items) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Letter to Thomas H. Seymour., March - April, 1859; (1 item) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Letters primarily to Thomas H. Seymour with related material., May - June, 1859; (8 items) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Letters primarily to Thomas H. Seymour (one in French)., July - August, 1859; (13 items) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., September, 1859; (27 items) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., October, 1859; (14 items) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., November, 1859; (29 items) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., December, 1859; (21 item) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Letters to and concerning Thomas H. Seymour., January, 1860; (26 items) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., February 1 - 20, 1860; (28 items) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., February 21 - 29, 1860; (18 items) (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., March 1 - 10, 1860; (21 items) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., March 11 - 31, 1860; (18 items) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., April, 1860; (22 items) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., May, 1860; (30 items) (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., June, 1860; (13 items) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., July, 1860; (11 items) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., August, 1860; (12 items) (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., September, 1860; (11 item) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Letters primarily to Thomas H. Seymour., October, 1860; (25 items) (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., November, 1860; (13 items) (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour and Mary Seymour., December, 1860; (6 items) (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., January, 1861; (19 items) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., February, 1861; (15 items) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., March - April, 1861; (13 items) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., May - June, 1861; (17 items) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., July, 1861; (16 items) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., August, 1861; (21 item) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., September, 1861; (14 items) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Letters to and concerning Thomas H. Seymour., October, 1861; (16 items) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., November, 1861; (10 items) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., December, 1861; (12 items) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., January 1 - 15, 1862; (21 items) (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour, some with attached news clippings., January 16 - 31, 1862; (16 items) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., February, 1862; (9 items) (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., March, 1862; (20 items) (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., April, 1862; (15 items) (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour, including memorial poem to Henry L. Miller by S. E. Knowles., May, 1862; (14 items) (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., June, 1862; (3 items) (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., July, 1862; (24 items) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., August, 1862; (10 items) (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., September, 1862; (18 items) (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour; autograph of Franklin Pierce., October, 1862; (3 items) (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour; letters to John Danforth with supporting documents; newspaper clippings., November, 1862; (18 items) (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., December, 1862; (19 items) (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., January 1 - 15, 1863; (26 items) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., January 16 - 31, 1863; (7 items) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., February 1 - 20, 1863; (27 items) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., February 21 - 28, 1863; (19 items) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., March 1 - 10, 1863; (17 items) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., March 11 - 20, 1863; (25 items) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., March 21 - 31, 1863; (27 items) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour with supporting material., April, 1863; (24 items) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour with supporting material., May, 1863; (19 items) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., June, 1863; (22 items) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour; letter from Franklin Pierce., July, 1863; (14 items) (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., August, 1863; (28 items) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., September, 1863; (19 items) (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., October, 1863; (15 items) (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., November, 1863; (27 items) (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., December, 1863; (23 items) (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., January, 1864; (25 items) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., February, 1864; (17 items) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., March, 1864; (14 items) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., April, 1864; (11 item) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., May, 1864; (17 items) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour, June, 1864; (4 items) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Letters to William Seymour and Thomas H. Seymour., July - December, 1864; (10 items) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour; letters to William Seymour; letter to Mary Seymour., 1865; (20 items) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., January - February, 1866; (15 items) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., March - April, 1866; (18 items) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., May - June, 1866; (9 items) (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., July, 1866; (18 items) (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour with related news clippings., August, 1866; (20 items) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., September - October, 1866; (20 items) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., November, 1866; (15 items) (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., December, 1866; (10 items) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., January, 1867; (18 items) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour; letter from Seymour to Ashbel Smith., February, 1867; (19 items) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., March, 1867; (21 item) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and concerning Thomas H. Seymour., April, 1867; (21 item) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour with supporting material; copy of Speech of Gen. James H. Clanton of Montgomery, in reply to Senator Wilsonof Massachusetts, May, 1867; (18 items) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., June, 1867; (16 items) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., July, 1867; (16 items) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., August, 1867; (18 items) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., September, 1867; (21 item) (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour (one in French)., October, 1867; (16 items) (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., November, 1867; (26 items) (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour., December, 1867; (19 items) (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour with related material., January - February, 1868; (18 items) (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Letters to and from Thomas H. Seymour with related material., March - April, 1868; (20 items) (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour with related material., May - August, 1868; (6 items) (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour, undated, A, [18--]; (33 items) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Letters primarily to Thomas H. Seymour, undated, B., [18-]; (35 items) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour, undated, C, [18-]; (15 items) (Box 9, Folder 3)